Guide to the Records of the Institute of African American Affairs RG.9.8
New York University Archives
- Series IV: Audiovisual Recordings
  - Subseries A: The Soul of Reason Audio Recordings
    - Jackson Christmas, Dr. June -- Commissioner of Mental Health Services in New York City., 1977 August 9; RG9.8-131; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 50, Folder 131)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Dr. June Jackson Christmas discuss the increase in mental health issues within the Black community following the recent economic crisis. They also discuss the programs available to the Black community to treat these issues.
    - Thompson, Dr. Leon -- Director of Education Activities for the New York Philharmonic., 1977 August 23; RG9.8-130; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 50, Folder 130)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Dr. Leon Thompson discuss how Lincoln Center is recognizing and honoring the Black presence in classical music.
    - Grymes, Sandra -- North East Regional Director for Planned Parenthood Federation, Inc., 1977 August 30; RG9.8-129; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 50, Folder 129)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Sandra Grymes discuss population growth as a major social problem.
    - Patterson, Jamelle and Dianne McDonald -- Founder of the Patterson School, and an instructor at the Patterson School., 1977 September 6; RG9.8-128; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 50, Folder 128)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr., Jamelle Patterson, and Dianne McDonald discuss alternative forms of education for Black youth, using the Patterson School, a private school for Black students, as an example.
    - Byer, Lavenia, Jeanette Fields, and Andrew Henderson -- Coordinator, Chairperson and Consultant from the Freedom Funds United Foundation., 1977 September 13; RG9.8-201; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 54, Folder 201)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr., Lavenia Byer, Andrew Henderson, and Jeanette Fields speak about the programs of the Freedom Funds Cultural Train, which were developed to bring the Black community together and to create a more positive image of the community.
    - Williams, Franklin -- President of the Phelps-Stokes Fund and former United States Ambassador to Ghana., 1977 September 20; RG9.8-163; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 53, Folder 163)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Franklin Williams discuss the stuggle for majority rule in Southern Africa and its effects on the rest of the world.
    - Henderson, Butler T. -- Executive Director of the Earl Warren Legal Training Program of the NAACP's Legal Defense and Education Fund., 1977 September 22; RG9.8-23; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 40, Folder 23)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Butler T. Henderson discuss the recruitment and training of Black lawyers.
    - Lenior, Henry and Livingston Francis -- Group Vice President of the YMCA of Greater New York and the Executive Director of the Harlem YMCA., 1977 September 22; RG9.8-21; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 40, Folder 21)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr., Henry Lenior, and Livingston Francis begin by discussing the Harlem YMCA dinner that was organized to honor Secretary of War Clifford Alexander, but they also discuss more generally how the programming of the YMCA has expanded, allowing the YMCA to become the social instiution for the Black community rather than just a health club.
    - Webb, Dr. Arnold -- Executive Director of the Division of Education of New York City's Board of Education., 1977 September 29; RG9.8-176; Format: Reel TRT: 30:30 (Box 55, Folder 176)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Dr. Arnold Webb discuss the 1977-1978 school year budget concerns, as well as issues surrounding racial integration.
    - Williams, Charles T. "Chuck" -- Vice President of the Schenley Affiliated Brands Corporation and Member of the Board for the Jackie Robinson Foundation., 1977 October 6; RG9.8-25; Format: Reel TRT: 29:57 (Box 40, Folder 25)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Charles T. "Chuck" Williams discuss how Jackie Robinson -- a man they both knew well -- created opportunities for Black athletes, as well as fought for social, economic, and political justice for all Americans. However, a cause of particular interest to Robinson was providing educational and recreational opportunities for economically-deprived Black children. As a result, the Jackie Robinson Foundation identified its objective as providing support for Black children through an internship program.
    - Jordan, Richard -- Director of the Urban Services Division of the Boys Clubs of America., 1977 October 13; RG9.8-26; Format: Reel TRT: 30.00 (Box 40, Folder 26)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Richard Jordan discuss how the urban divisions of the Boys Clubs of American seek to offer youths an alternative residence, a home away from home, as well as access to other services and leisurely activities.
    - Turner, Robert -- firefighter and President of the Vulcan Society., 1977 October 25; RG9.8-167; Format: Reel TRT: 29:59 (Box 55, Folder 167)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Robert Turner discuss the recruitment of minority firefighters.
    - Dempsey, Ellen and Charlotte Frank -- Project Coordinator for the New York City Bicentennial Corporation and a representative from the New York City Board of Education "Scholars Series.", 1977 November 3; RG9.8-91; Format: Reel TRT: 30:02 (Box 41, Folder 91)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr., Ellen Dempsey, and Charlotte Frank discuss curriculumn development in New York City schools with discipline issues and overcrowding.
    - Barnes, Arthur and Reverend Frederick E. Dennard -- President of the Urban Coalition and Executive Director of Harlem Interfaith Counseling Service., 1977 November 3; RG9.8-27; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 40, Folder 27)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr., Reverend Frederick E. Dennard, and Arthur Barnes discuss the mental health and spiritual guidance services offered by the New York Urban Coalition's Interfaith Counseling Services project in Harlem.
    - Lynch, Professor Hollis -- Political Scientist and African History Specialist from Columbia University., 1977 November 17; RG9.8-28; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 40, Folder 28)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Professor Hollis Lynch speak about the political state of South Africa and its impact, especially its economic affect on the rest of the world.
    - Huggins, Dr. Nathan -- Professor of History at Columbia University and author of Black Odyssey., 1977 December 1; RG9.8-29; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 40, Folder 29)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Dr. Nathan Huggins speak about the reception of Huggins' book Black Odyssey, which tells the history of the African-American people with an emphasis on slavery.
    - Higginson, Vy -- Founder and Publisher of Unique New York magazine., 1977 December 18; RG9.8-78; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 41, Folder 78)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Vy Higginson discuss Higginson's transition from radio personality to publisher of Unique New York, a lifestyle magazine and entertainment guide for the New York's Black community.
    - McDougald, Drew -- Director of the Queens Branch of the New York Urban League and Carlisle Towery and Executive Director of the Greater Jamaica Development Corporation., 1977; RG9.8-24; Format: Reel TRT: 30:10 (Box 40, Folder 24)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr., Drew McDougald, and Carlisle Towery discuss the social development and the economic potential for the borrough of Queens. Of interest was the closing of Macy's Jamaica branch.
    - McIntyre, Diane -- choreographer for the Negro Ensemble Company's production of The Great MacDaddy and founder of the company Sounds and Motion., 1977; RG9.8-200; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 54, Folder 200)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Diane McIntyre discuss the field of choreography and McIntyre's company Sounds and Motion.
    - Saidy, Jay, Bakari Sidibe, and Sam Kinte -- journalist for the Gambian News Bulletin, Minister of Cultural Affairs, and the Gambian cousin of author Alex Haley., 1977; RG9.8-142; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 53, Folder 142)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr., Jay Saidy, Sidibe Bakari, and Sam Kinte discuss the historical novel Roots, as well as Gambia's mission to bridge cultural ties between their country and the United States.
    - Chance, Cathy -- Special Assistant for Urban Affairs at the Metropolitan Museum of Art., 1978 January 19; RG9.8-203; Format: Reel TRT: 29:53 (Box 54, Folder 203)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Cathy Chance discuss programming of the Metropolitan Museum of Art that is relevant to the Black and Hispanic communities of New York.
    - Wilkins, Roger -- Urban Affairs Columnist for The New York Times., 1978 January 19; RG9.8-204; Format: Reel TRT: 29:55 (Box 54, Folder 204)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Roger Wilkins discuss the affect of the Carter administration on the Black community.
    - Huggins, Dr. Nathan -- Professor of History at Columbia University and author of Black Odyssey., 1978 June 8; RG9.8-37; Format: Reel TRT: 29:30 (Box 40, Folder 37)
      During the 1970s, books on slavery proliferated. Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Dr. Nathan Huggins discuss the argument Huggins makes in his book Black Odyssey. He argues America was a slave society rather than a free society, or rather slavery was an indigenous part of the development of America.
    - Barron, Allan -- Publisher of Black Sports Magazine., 1978; RG9.8-36; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 40, Folder 36)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Allan Barron discuss how sports became a major part of life in Black America.
    - Butts, Dr. Hugh -- Director of the Bronx Psychiatric Center., 1978; RG9.8-100; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 41, Folder 100, Box Access 13, Item 10)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Dr. Hugh Butts discuss the lack of mental health resources available to the economically-deprived communities in the Bronx.
    - Davis, Gordon -- Commissioner of Parks and Recreation for the City of New York., 1978; RG9.8-228; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 228)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Gordon Davis discuss the extensive park system of New York City.
    - Jones, Robert Earle -- actor, athlete, scholar, and patron of the arts., 1978; RG9.8-230; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 230)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Robert Earle Jones discuss Jones' background and career.
    - Presley, Calvin -- Executive Director of Opportunities Industrialization Center, Inc., 1978; RG9.8-229; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 229)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Calvin Presley speak about the Opportunities Industrial Center, Inc., which began as a protest movement in Philadelphia in the 1960s for a more diverse workplace.
    - Cudsville, Donald -- President of the Harlem Urban Development Corporation (HUDC)., Unknown; RG9.8-108; Format: Reel (Box 41, Folder 108, Box Access 13, Item 10)
      Dr. Roscoe C. Brown, Jr. and Donald Cudsville discuss the Harlem Urban Development Corporation's improvement of housing and economic conditions in Harlem.
    - Unlabeled., RG 9.8-87 (Box 41, Folder 87)
    - Unlabeled., RG 9.8-95; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 41, Folder 95)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-92; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 41, Folder 92)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-30; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 40, Folder 30)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-31; Format: Reel TRT: 30 min (Box 40, Folder 31)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-32; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 40, Folder 32)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-77; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 41, Folder 77)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-103; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 41, Folder 103)
    - Unlabeled., RG 9.8-107; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 41, Folder 107)
    - Unlabeled., 1977; RG 9.8-96; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 41, Folder 96)
    - Unlabeled., RG 9.8-104 (Box 41, Folder 104)
    - Unlabeled., RG 9.8-99; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 41, Folder 99)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-93; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 41, Folder 93)
    - Unlabeled., Rg 9.8-80; Format: Reel TRT: 30:04 (Box 41, Folder 80)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-211; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 211)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-180; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 55, Folder 180)
    - Unlabeled., RG 9.8-202; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 54, Folder 202)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-205; Format: Reel TRT: 30:01 (Box 54, Folder 205)
    - Unlabeled., RG 9.8-206; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 54, Folder 206)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-212; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 212)
    - Unlabeled., 1974; RG9.8-213; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 213)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-214; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 214)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-215; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 215)
    - Unlabeled., 1974; RG9.8-216; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 216)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-217; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 217)
    - Unlabeled., 1974; RG9.8-218; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 218)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-219; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 219)
    - Unlabeled., 1976; RG9.8-220; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 220)
    - Unlabeled., 1976; RG9.8-221; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 221)
    - Unlabeled., 1976; RG9.8-222; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 222)
    - Unlabeled., 1976; RG9.8-223; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 223)
    - Unlabeled., 1977; RG9.8-225; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 51, Folder 225)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; 9.8-226; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 226)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-227; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 227)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-231; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 231)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-232; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 232)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-233; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 233)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-234; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 234)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-235; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 235)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-236; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 236)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-237; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 37, Folder 237)
    - Unlabeled., 1974; RG9.8-238; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 238)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-239; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 239)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-240; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 240)
    - Unlabeled., 1975; RG9.8-241; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 241)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-242; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 242)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-243; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 243)
    - Unlabeled., 1976; RG9.8-244; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 244)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-245; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 245)
    - Unlabeled., 1977; RG9.8-246; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 246)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-247; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 57, Folder 247)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-248; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 36, Folder 248)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-249; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 36, Folder 249)
    - Unlabeled., 1977; RG9.8-250; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 36, Folder 250)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-251; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 36, Folder 251)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-252; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 36, Folder 252)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-253; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 36, Folder 253)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-254; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 254)
    - Unlabeled., 1976; RG9.8-255; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 255)
    - Unlabeled., 1976; RG9.8-256; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 256)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-257; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 257)
    - Unlabeled., 1975; RG9.8-258; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 258)
    - Unlabeled., 1973; RG9.8-259; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 259)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-260; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 260)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-33; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 40, Folder 33)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-102; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 41, Folder 102)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-127; Format: Reel TRT: Unknown (Box 50, Folder 127)
    - Unlabeled., 1974; RG9.8-261; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 261)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-172; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 55, Folder 172)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG 9.8-173; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 55, Folder 173)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-15; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Unlabeled., 1974; RG9.8-262; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 56, Folder 262)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-35; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 40, Folder 35)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-14; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-263; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 49, Folder 263)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-74; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 41, Folder 74)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-3; Format: Reel TRT: unknown (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Unlabeled., 1978; RG9.8-34; Format: Reel TRT: 30:00 (Box 40, Folder 34)
    - Unlabeled., 1976; RG9.8-264; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 49, Folder 264)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-265; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 49, Folder 265)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-266; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 49, Folder 266)
    - Unlabeled., RG9.8-4; Format: Reel TRT: Unknown (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Subseries B: Other Audio Recordings
    - Teach-In, reel 1, 1965 May 5; RG9-8_ref4426; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
      Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
      1/4 inch open reel audio tape
    - Teach-In, reel 2, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In, reel 3, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
      Format: 1/4 inch open reel audio tape
    - Teach-In, reel 4, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In, reel 5, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In, reel 6, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In, reel 7, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels; Format: 1/4 inch audio reel (Box 39)
    - Teach-In, reel 8, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
      Physical Facet note
    - Teach-In, reel 9, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In, reel 10, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
    - Teach-In, reel 11, 1965 May 5; 1 sound tape reels (Box 39)
- Series V: Administrative Files
  - Anna Deavere Smith, 1996-1998
  - Africana Studies, 1995-1996
  - Carribean Cultural Center, 1995-1996
  - Louis Massiah Project (with Robin D.G. Kelley), 1996-1997
  - Dellon Project, 1996-1997
  - Clips, 1995-1996
  - Michele Fabre, 1996-1997
  - Leon Higginbotham, undated
  - Black Intellectuals Conference, 1996
  - Black Renaissance Celebration, 1997
  - Black Thought in Progress (Julius Lester), 1996
  - Originals (Press Releases and Promotional Material), 1998-1999
  - Travel, 1998-1999
  - Distinguished Scholar-in-Residence Wole Soyinka Correspondence, 1998-1999
  - Distinguished Scholar-in-Residence Wole Soyinka Februrary 19th Event, 1999
  - Artist in Residence Mykelti Williamson Accomodations Information, 1998-1999
  - Haiti on Screen Contact Lists, 2003
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Accomodations, Information, and Bios, 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Dinner October 6 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Correspondence, 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Inquiries/Projects (Empty), 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Flyers Invoice, 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Misc, 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Dinner, 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Misc, 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Biographies, 1998
  - Artist in Residence - Danny Glover - Alfre Woodard Correspondence, 1998
  - Carby, Hazel. Reconstructing Womanhood: The Emergence of the African American Woman Novelist, Undated
  - Paul Robeson, 1999
  - Artist in Residence - Feb 19th, 1998
  - Thulani Davis Artist & Society December 1st Event, 1998
  - Praying at Different Altars, Artist & Society Series, Undated
  - Projects - Gloria King Allen, 1999
  - Sista Sista - Toni Morrison, 1999
  - France in Africa/Africa in France - Tahar BenJelloun, 1995-1998
  - Sports Matters - Programmatic, 1997-1998
  - Sports Matters - Press Release, 1998
  - Sports Matters - Misc, 1997-1998
  - Sports Matters - Correspondence, 1997-1998
  - Sports Matters - Flyers, Brochures, Calendar, 1997-1998
  - Basketball Project - Budget, 1997-1998
  - Basketball Project - Correspondence, 1997-1998
  - Basketball Project - Misc., 1997
  - Projects - James Reynolds, 1999
  - Artist in Residence - Misc., 1996-1997
  - Thulani Davis / Lila Wallace, 1996-1998
  - Artist in Residence - Cassandra Wilson, 1998-1999
  - 1999 Film Screening
  - Annual Planning Report, 2002-2003
  - Lorna Simpson, 2002
  - Bios, 1998-1999
  - Reception Schedule, 1997-1998
  - Africana Studies Celebration (Book Signing), 1999
  - IAAA Events, 1997-1998
  - Habib Koite, 2001
  - Black Genius, 1998
  - Black Genius - Misc, 1997-1998
  - Black Genius - Development/Funding, 1997-1998
  - Black Genius - Correspondence, 1997-1998
  - Black Genius - Misc, 1998-1999
  - Black Genius - Misc, 1998-1999
  - Black Genius - Bios, 1997-1998
  - Black Genius - Misc, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Bios, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Brochures/Flyers, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Development/Funding, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Contracts, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Spike Lee, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Haki Madhubuti, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Julianne Malveaux, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Walter Mosley, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Randall Robinson, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Anna Deavere Smith, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Media, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Proposal, 1996
  - Black Genius - Photos, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Nathan Cummings Proposal, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Receptions, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Farai Chideya, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Stanley Crouch, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - George Curry, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Angela Davis, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Joycelyn Elders, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - bell hooks, 1996-1997
  - Black Genius - Hazel Carby, 1992
  - Faculty Reading - Printed Material, 1998
  - Faculty Reading - Correspondence, 1998
  - Faculty Reading - Reception Menus, 1998
  - Faculty Reading - Invitation List, 1998
  - Faculty Reading - Invoices, 1997-1998
  - Black Aesthetic, 2001
  - Slave Routes - Executive Summary, 1999
  - Slave Routes - Funding Dinner Responses, 1999
  - IAAA Events and Promotional Materials, 1994-1995